<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         version="5.0">
<info>
  <title>DocBook Documents</title>
  <h:link xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          rel="stylesheet" href="./css/defguide.css"/>
</info>

<para>This repository contains specifications and other documentation related to
DocBook. These are generally requirements, background papers, and working drafts.
</para>

<section xml:id="transclusion">
<title>Transclusion</title>

<para>“Transclusion” describes the process by which one document
incorporates another by reference. In XML, this is most commonly done
with XInclude. The presence of IDs and ID/IDREF links in an XML
document complicates the transclusion process. Transcluding a document
or fragment (for example, a warning or procedure) more than once may
introduce multiple elements with the same ID. That, in turn, makes
IDREF links to those IDs more complicated.</para>

<para>The transclusion specification describes a relatively
light-weight mechanism by which a document author can automatically
transform IDs and IDREFs to resolve duplicate IDs and clarify the
linking relationships.</para>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry>
<term><link xlink:href="transclusion.html">DocBook Transclusion</link></term>
<listitem>
<para>The syntax, semantics, and processing model for the DocBook transclusion mechanism.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term><link xlink:href="transclusion-requirements.html">Requirements for transclusion in DocBook</link></term>
<listitem>
<para>A summary of uses-cases for transclusion of content in DocBook documents.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
</section>

<section xml:id="iso690">
<title>ISO 690 Bibliographies</title>

<para>Evidence suggests that Jana Dvořáková published a
description of how to use DocBook to produce ISO 690 bibliographies.
It was lost from the wiki sometime circa 2012, it’s been recovered here
as <link xlink:href="iso690.html">Bibliography acorrding to ISO 690
and ISO 690-2 standards</link>.</para>
</section>

</article>
